{
    "id": "5a63a66f8cb14639b5a679bd3d077ac7",
    "title": "Intermediate Level Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She is ……………………. to take her own decisions now.",
            "description": "When enough modifies an adjective, it goes after that adjective.",
            "answers": [
                "enough mature",
                "mature enough",
                "too mature"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9d39580553fa41b7b26cd51c9e6c9503"
        },
        {
            "question": "Girls mature ………………………….. than boys.",
            "description": "Earlier is the correct comparative expression.",
            "answers": [
                "more early",
                "earlier",
                "more earlier"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4f42286106da45a08a0d4a3e2c5d5f46"
        },
        {
            "question": "The body ………………………. maturity earlier than the mind.",
            "description": "There is no preposition after reach.",
            "answers": [
                "reaches",
                "reaches at",
                "reaches to"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "579f99ddb06c428f9c2c0f62aed05c7e"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………… we will see you tomorrow.",
            "description": "Maybe means perhaps. May in may be is an auxiliary verb indicating probability.",
            "answers": [
                "Maybe",
                "May be",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ee59b92ca1384977bf21bca978522368"
        },
        {
            "question": "Many elderly people don’t have the …………………………. to travel.",
            "description": "Means can mean money, resources or funds.",
            "answers": [
                "mean",
                "means",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a89e3cf06d9d4581b4af168c5d5a4d00"
        },
        {
            "question": "How could anyone be so ……………………..?",
            "description": "Mean can mean malicious or vicious.",
            "answers": [
                "mean",
                "means",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "39fa0b792f724663b9fb150dc17d4cd6"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t want anyone to ………………………. in my affairs.",
            "description": "To meddle is to interfere.",
            "answers": [
                "meddle",
                "mettle",
                "medal"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c21b35751e574b0782c6100990e0458c"
        },
        {
            "question": "It takes a lot of ………………………. to fight bulls.",
            "description": "Mettle means courage.",
            "answers": [
                "meddle",
                "metal",
                "mettle"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "e25d45222aa74640b93133e6d3d37b0c"
        },
        {
            "question": "The lawyer tried to ………………………….. between the company and the union.",
            "description": "To mediate is to intervene or negotiate. To meditate is to think, ponder or reflect.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "mediate",
                "meditate",
                "modulate"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "34c24db4c5874b0188e1e0f731ab0e30"
        },
        {
            "question": "She spends hours admiring ……………………….. in the mirror.",
            "description": "We use the reflexive pronoun when the object refers to the same person as the subject.",
            "answers": [
                "her",
                "herself",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0c0eb1394ca74fe99f5bc786506a367f"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t approve of whisky but I am not averse …………………….. a glass of wine now and then.",
            "description": "Averse is followed by to.",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "to",
                "with"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f88b9f181b7c42f298b9ecb7561f051d"
        },
        {
            "question": "Cats have an aversion ………………………. wet.",
            "description": "The to here is a preposition. When to is a preposition, it is followed by a noun or ing form. ",
            "answers": [
                "to get",
                "to getting",
                "of getting"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c874f6334db84a10b10d51019f47a2d0"
        }
    ]
}